dicardiology.com 2017-10-04

# Privacy Policy | Scranton Gillette Communications

Scranton Gillette Communications, Inc. (SGC) understands the importance of your privacy and that is why protecting the personal information you, our users, submit is a priority. SGC developed its privacy policy with you in mind to protect your privacy concerns as well as address our legitimate business interests with the use and collection of information.

Please review the entire policy. This policy may change periodically so check back with us.

**SGC's Collection of User Information**

User information provided to us is obtained by:

• Personal information (e.g., name, e-mail address, mailing address, industry, occupation) that you supply when subscribing to, registering for or purchasing products and services through our magazines or web sites;

• Activity and preference tracking information (SGC utilizes cookies* and other aggregate activity logging to track this activity);

• Information regarding your interests.

SGC may research or acquire additional information on any user/subscriber as needed to provide targeted messaging and information.

Fairly common on the WWW is the tracking of user sessions while remaining anonymous, allowing private browsing and the submission of personal information. IP addresses also are not linked to any personal information although each site does log IP addresses and browser types for administration purposes. Registering with us will give you the opportunity to utilize our sites' products and services while allowing us to remain updated on your interests.

All of SGC's sites offer links to other Web sites, which we encourage you to utilize, but be sure to read their privacy policies for changes from ours. Advertisers, sponsors and any other sites that may link to our sites are administered and provided by advertisers, sponsors or other sites and are not controlled by SGC.

* Cookie: A small amount of data sent from a web server to a browser to be stored on that computer's hard drive. Cookies make SGC able to track your interests as well as remember your user password. Individual cookies can track a site’s collective views, allowing us to learn what our users are interested in. Most web browsers accept cookies but they can be turned off at the risk of debilitating your access to certain features on the sites. (Personal information cannot be stored with cookies.)

**SGC's Use of Personal Information**

Personal information collected by SGC and stored in its databases is used for future contact. Uses may include new products and services, site updates, status of orders, etc. Data collected from cookies and browser identification provides the user's demographic information so SGC can make improvements to its sites as well as better customize it to our audiences. Personal information also may be used for purposes such as editorial, marketing and promotions, product development, tracking hits, etc.

**Sharing Information With Third Parties**

SGC may share volunteered personal information to third parties who provide products and services that SGC believes users would be interested in purchasing or receiving more information about. You are given the ability to "opt-out" of any of our individual email lists/groups and/or to opt-out of one of our major email categories (editorial messages, internal marketing, marketing partner emails, etc.) as well as being able to totally opt out of everything we send from any of our brands (link at the bottom of the page for that). By not selecting to opt-out, you give SGC permission to provide personal information as part of our visitor and subscriber lists for each such third party to use if we believe subscribers would be interested in receiving an e-mail or other written correspondence from any such third party. To protect the rights of SGC and our users, SGC will provide personal information if the law requires, despite the opt-out option.

If you are requesting assistance, product information, white papers, case studies or brochures, your contact information may be shared with the developer of the relevant product, content, or software. Some materials that are available for download on SGC sites, like white papers, product demonstrations, case studies, and product literature, are offered in conjunction with a partner company. This information is shared with the partner company so that they may provide you with the material you requested.

SGC may share information collected from cookies and other browser technology or IP addresses to aid our advertisers in tracking users' needs and interests as well as the advertisers reach.

**Users Right to Opt-Out**

Should you, the user, wish to opt-out, just select the opt-out option whenever asked, to be sure your personal information will not be made available or used by third parties. You, the user, also have the option to opt-out by sending a letter or e-mail stating that you want to opt-out of any third party mailings.

All requests should be sent to

SGC

Privacy Manager

3030 W Salt Creek Ln. Suite 201

Arlington Heights, IL 60005
